# Miguel Ángel García

Web: <a href="http://miguel.ga">http://miguel.ga</a>

Location: Argentina, Capital Federal

LinkedIn: <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/zzmike">http://www.linkedin.com/in/zzmike</a>
GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/miguelgarcia">https://github.com/miguelgarcia</a>



## **Profile**

I'm a Licentiate in Computer Science from University of Buenos Aires, graduated on 2016. I've been interested in computers and technology since I was a kid and I've been working as a software developer and IT consultant since 2004.

I like building things using open source technologies and working on projects that allow me to learn. I consider myself a fast learner and have no problem learning new languages or technologies.

I'm based in Buenos Aires, Argentina and prefer to work remotely.

### **Education**

**Licentiate in Computer Science** (equivalent to Master degree in USA: 6 years plus thesis) graduated on 2016 at "Faculty of Exact and Natural Sciences, University of Buenos Aires". GPA: 8.5/10

**Licentiate thesis**: "Techniques and methodologies for vision systems implementation on All Programmable SoCs using High Level Synthesis" (<a href="https://github.com/miguelgarcia/tesis-apsoc">https://github.com/miguelgarcia/tesis-apsoc</a>)

The thesis received these awards:

- •1st award at the JAIIO45 "Students Thesis Contest"
- •1st mention by CESSI (Argentina Software industry companies organizations) at the JAIIO45

#### Courses Taken

- Learning GO LinkedIn Learning
- SCRUM: The Basics LinkedIn Learning
- Learn DevOPs: The complete Kubernetes Course UDEMY

## **Professional Experience**

#### Fluge1.it: Software engineer / DevOps

Development of tools around the Kubernetes ecosystem, like custom operators, helm packages, and command line tools using Go and Python.

**ENACOM** (Ente Nacional de Comunicaciones, Argentina government): IT Consultant 2017-now

Design and implementation of a web platform to ease the reception and processing of information from telecommunication providers using Python, PostgreSQL, AMQP, Docker and Bonita BPMs.

#### Freelancer Software Developer / Consultant

2017-now

Development of web applications for medium sized companies and organizations using Python, React, SQL and NoSQL databases.

#### Enjambre Bit SRL: Co-founder / Full stack developer

2015-2017

Enjambre Bit is a custom software development firm founded by me and three colleagues on 2015. I departed Enjambre on 2017 to focus on other projects.

Applications development for various customers using Ember JS, Electron, Python and Docker. The most important project was <a href="http://pilasbloques.program.ar/">http://pilasbloques.program.ar/</a> a platform to help kids learn computer programming using blocks.

## ANSES Conectar Igualdad, Huayra Linux: Linux developer

2012-2015

Conectar Igualdad was an Argentina government program to supply each high school student with a laptop computer. Huayra GNU/Linux is a Debian based Linux distro built for Conectar Igualdad laptops.

During my time at the Huayra team I did multiple tasks, like:

• Desktop applications development with QT and GTK.

- Customization of applications to ease use on small screens by students.
- Kernel drivers test and packaging using DKMS.
- Create and maintain DEB packages.
- Hardware prototypes evaluation.

#### PressEnter Coop: Full stack developer

2012-2015

PressEnter was a cooperative custom software development firm. As a full stack developer there I built applications for various customers. I also took part in projects planning.

- Web applications development using Python and PHP5 (Django and Symfony2).
- Projects management.

#### Education Ministry (GCBA): PHP developer

2008-2012

Buenos Aires City Government (GCBA) Education Ministry is responsible for the education of 700.000 students in ~2300 schools. I was part of the team that developed web applications (using Symfony1) to ease management.

- Development web applications to manage students inscriptions, grades and teachers information.
- Development of the application that provides users unified login and security management.

#### Sociedad Hebraica Argentina: PHP developer

2004-2008

Sociedad Hebraica Argentina is a social club with around 8000 members. My job there was to create and maintain an ecosystem of applications for the club administration.

- Development of a custom PHP4 frameworks
- Design and develop accounting, invoicing, reports, members and suppliers physical access control and booking web applications
- Train new developers

## **Personal Projects**

On my spare time I enjoy doing small projects and solving coding problems for learning and keeping up to date.

Check my GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/miguelgarcia">https://github.com/miguelgarcia</a> to see my open source projects and collaborations.

## Skills List

This is a non - exhaustive list of my skills:

Languages: Python, Go, C++, PHP, Javascript

Frameworks and libraries: Flask, Django, pytest, kubernetes client, React,

OpenCV

Infrastructure: Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, Terraform, Ansible

Data bases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Other: Scrum, CI, Git, Linux programming, Apache, Nginx, Bonita BPMS

## Languages

Spanish: Native
English: Advanced